<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AML-CS | Uninorte</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on AML-CS | Uninorte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 22:16:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aml-cs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup mpi4py in OpenHPC</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/posts/setup-mpi4py-in-openhpc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 22:16:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/posts/setup-mpi4py-in-openhpc/</guid><description>&lt;p>How to setup mpi4py using miniconda in Centos 7 - OpenHPC. Including examples for run an Interactive session and SBATCH.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to install C and FORTRAN versions of NetCDF in Ubuntu 10.15</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/posts/install-c-and-fortran-netcdf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 17:59:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/posts/install-c-and-fortran-netcdf/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Awards</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/awards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/awards/</guid><description> Best Workshop Paper Award. A Surrogate Model Based On Mixtures Of Taylor Expansions For Trust Region Based Methods. ICCS 2017, Zurich, Zwitserland, June 2017. More info: http://www.iccs-meeting.org/iccs2017/awards/</description></item><item><title>Current Students</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/current-students/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/current-students/</guid><description>Randy Steven Consuegra Ortega, M.Sc. in Computer Science. Data-Driven Models for Variational Data Assimilation. Website Juan Sebastian Rodriguez Donado, M.Sc. in Computer Science. Data Assimilation Method for Air Quality Estimation. Website Andres Felipe Movilla Obregon, M.Sc. in Computer Science. Website Omar Angel Mejia Suarez, M.Sc. in Computer Science. Data Assimilation Method for Air Quality Estimation. Website Sebastián Molano, B.</description></item><item><title>Former Students</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/former-students/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/former-students/</guid><description>Juan C. Calabria Sarmiento, Ph.D. in Computer Science, Data Assimilation Methods for Wind Energy Potential Estimation. (2020). Luis Gabriel Guzman Reyes, Ph.D. in Computer Science, Shrinkage Covariance Matrix Estimation in Ensemble-Based Data Assimilation. (2020). Website Rolando Beltran Arrieta, Ph.D. in Computer Science, Non-Linear Data Assimilation via Sampling Methods. (2019). Luis Ernesto Morales Retat, M.Sc. in Computer Science, Soft Computing Methods for Optimal Radius of Influence Estimation in Ensemble Based Data Assimilation.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Nino-Ruiz, E. D., A Data-Driven Localization Method for Ensemble Based Data Assimilation. Journal of Computational Science, Vol. 51, 101328., Elsevier, (2021). (HTML)
Lopez-Restrepo, S., Nino-Ruiz, E.D., Guzman-Reyes, L.G. et al. An efficient ensemble Kalman Filter implementation via shrinkage covariance matrix estimation: exploiting prior knowledge. Computational Geosciences (2021). (HTML)
Elias D. Nino-Ruiz, Hybrid Ensemble Kalman Filter and Markov Chain Monte Carlo Implementations for Non-Gaussian Data Assimilation, International Journal of Artificial Intelligence, 2020 Autumn (October) , Volume 18, Number 2.</description></item><item><title>Talk Series in Computer Science and Applications</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/talks/talk-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/talks/talk-series/</guid><description>31/07/2020 - Spanish Algunos Aspectos Teóricos y Prácticos de la Asimilación de Datos en la Predicción Meteorológica. Centro de Modelización Matemática (MODEMAT)l, Ecuador. 14/08/2020 - English Scientific Machine Learning and its Potentials. Associate Professor, Willamette University, USA. 28/08/2020 - English Nature-Inspired Algorithms: Challenges and Open Problems, Senior Research Scientist at National Physical Laboratory, MiddleSex University, UK. 11/09/2020 - English Calibration and Kalman Filtering for Tide and Storm-Surge Models.</description></item><item><title>Talks by Dr. Elias Nino-Ruiz</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/talks/elias-ni%C3%B1o/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/talks/elias-ni%C3%B1o/</guid><description>15/05/2020 - Métodos de Machine Learning e Inteligencia Artificial: Oportunidades Para Estimar el Impacto del SAR-COV-2 en Colombia - (Spanish). Video
19/09/2019 - Efficient Implementation of Ensemble Based Methods - First International Workshop on Data Assimilation for Decision Making, Barranquilla, Colombia (ENGLISH). Video
22/01/2019 - Ensemble Kalman Filter Based On A Modified Cholseky Decomposition, ISDA 2019 - 7th International Symposium on Data Assimilation, RIKEN R-CCS, Kobe, Japan (ENGLISH).</description></item></channel></rss>