<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Call-for-papers on AML-CS | Uninorte</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/call-for-papers/</link><description>Recent content in Call-for-papers on AML-CS | Uninorte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://aml-cs.github.io/call-for-papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SPECIAL ISSUE OF INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE (IJAI) ON MACHINE LEARNING METHODS TO SOLVE INVERSE PROBLEMS</title><link>https://aml-cs.github.io/call-for-papers/ijai-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aml-cs.github.io/call-for-papers/ijai-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.scimagojr.com/journalsearch.php?q=19600166036&amp;amp;tip=sid&amp;amp;exact=no" title="SCImago Journal &amp;amp; Country Rank">&lt;img border="0" src="https://www.scimagojr.com/journal_img.php?id=19600166036" alt="SCImago Journal &amp;amp; Country Rank"/>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inverse Problems can be found in different branches of science. Many of them are related to estimating parameters in statistical models; for instance, a common practice is to tune parameters in partial differential equations or improve forecasts in sequential and variational data assimilation methods, all via noisy observations. Regardless of the context, many issues are raised during the estimation: the impact of sampling noise during the analysis, the non-linear relationship between observations and model variables, the computational cost of running numerical models, and the estimation of prior errors, among others. Machine Learning has become a powerful tool for parameter and state estimation in numerical models. In this context, we can find a pool of models that provide accurate estimates when combined with other information sources, for instance, numerical models. Besides, these methods can be employed to abstract error statistics from data and build statistical models that mimic the actual behavior of natural phenomena. In general, Machine Learning methods can be exploited in any context wherein complex relationships in variables (parameters or states) arise from data.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>